Nikolai Dorofeev

System Analyst

IT specialist of experience in wide range of technologies. Worked with different ecosystems: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, Java, C#. Integrated systems via REST API, SOAP, gRPC, RabbitMQ. Took lead role in creation of documentation for Kubernetes-based microservices solution.



Languages

- · English: Upper-Intermediate
- · Russian: Native

Skills









UML



Work Experience

Full-stack Developer Exactpro (Georgia)

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

- · Led development of an easy-to-deploy and easy-to-update docs web toolkit package based on Nuxt.is and Tailwind CSS.
- · Contributed to 50+ Vue.js components.
- Integrated applications with 3+ 3rd party solutions such as GitHub or Algolia using REST API.
- · Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements.
- Developed #1 architecture for providing traceability of digital assets between blockchains for Swift Hackathon 2022.
- Configured 10+ CI/CD pipelines for publishing static websites and npm packages via GitHub actions, GitLab CI.
- Mentored junior specialists and technical writers.

Full-stack Developer Exactpro

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- Developed a custom documentation portal with 7+ features for technical writers using Gridsome (Vue.js + GraphQL).
- Integrated applications with 3+ 3rd party solutions such as GitHub or Algolia.
- · Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements.
- Developed 10+ demonstration Python and Kotlin modules for th2 complex Kubernetes-based microservices framework with gRPC and RabbitMQ communication.
- Wrote 30+ clear and easy-to-understand documentation pages for complex Kubernetes-based - microservices framework
- Configured 10+ CI/CD pipelines for building and publishing static websites via GitHub actions and Jenkins

Full-stack Developer (Front-end heavy) WebSphere

Feb 2018 - Apr 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- · Implemented frontend architectures, utilizing Vue.js, to create scalable and modular web applications with 100+ components in total. Utilized Vuex for state management.
- · Ensured seamless user experiences across various devices, optimizing applications for desktops, tablets, and mobile devices.
- Contributed to 50+ REST API endpoints using Express.js, Fastify.
- Set up 70+ features integrations between the frontend and backend systems.
- Collaborated closely with UI/UX designers to transform wireframes into user-friendly interfaces.
- Wrote 200+ unit tests to verify the functionality of user interfaces, back-end processing, connectivity, and relational database interactions.

Projects

- tradeb0t: im Trading software with high integration possibilities
- th2-cli: CLI for managing th2 infrastructure in Kubernetes cluster
- tweetst0rm: 🐔 Simple app that uses GPT-3 for generating tweets.

Certificates

- Enterprise Patterns (foxminded.ua, May 2023): Course Page, Certificate, Verify Certificate
- Architecting With Google Kubernetes Engine (Coursera, Oct 2021): Certificate
- Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing (Google Digital Garage, Jul 2021): Certificate

Education

Information Systems And Technologies Tomsk Polytechnic University Sep 2018 - Jul 2022 (3 years 11 months)

Get a bachelor's degree in Information Systems and Technology in Business.